# Andrei Bychko

Senior/Lead .NET Developer / Tech Lead

Email: andrei.a.bychko@gmail.com

LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/andrei-a-bychko

# Summary

Senior/Lead Software Developer with 18+ years of enterprise experience in building .NET (C#, VB.NET, SQL with/without Entity Framework) software systems: fin-tech, SCADA, PLM.

Worked mostly with back-end, but also with different clients (desktop, WebForms, MVC), architectures, patterns and approaches (monolithic and microservices), cloud platforms (Azure and AWS), VCS (Perforce, TFS, SVN, GIT) and CI/CD systems (NANT, CC.NET, Jenkins and Azure DevOps), queue messaging systems (MSMQ, RabbitMQ, Kafka), file formats (XML, JSON, ZIP, XLS, XLSX, INI, CSV), graphics (WinAPI GDI, GDI+, OpenGL). I also had hands-on experience with: Assembler, Delphi, LISP, VHDL, MS Interops and OpenXML, log4net, RegEx, CUDA, Map+Reduce (BigData), MiniSAT, Solr.

Unit tests: NUnit, TDD.

About 5 y/exp developing architecture and writing requirements and specifications. Almost 1 year of leading team (PMI/waterfall and Agile/SAFe), mentoring teammates and conducting technical interviews.

Looking for challenging tasks in modern or legacy enterprise solutions.

### Education

Master's Degree in Computer Science

[Belarussian State University of Informatics and Radioelectronics, Belarus, 2018]

## Languages

- English (B2+)
- Russian, Belarussian (native)
- Polish (B1)

**Pet Project:** AabSemantics – open-source C# framework for semantic networks. <u>GitHub</u>, <u>wiki</u>, <u>NuGet package</u>.



## **Professional Experience**

# 02.2015 - 12.2020 and 04.2023-present

# Senior .NET Developer at Aras corp

PLM system

- Collected and validated technical requirements.
- Designed data models and algorithms to match these requirements.
- Wrote comprehensive specifications to describe them.
- Implemented all this stuff in C# code, refactored and bugfixed.
- Led development team of 2 dev + 1 QA, performed code reviews.
- Worked with 3<sup>rd</sup> party components (FullText, AI, etc), Jenkins and Azure DevOps pipelines.
- Created the whole Content Modelling Framework with Data Auto Migration subsystem. Well-documented, good-written, covered by unit tests, DAM really works and prevents data corruption.
- Managed to finish Graph Navigation project in 9 months (7 planned) despite work scope had been suddenly doubled two weeks before planned release.
- Rewrote existing data synchronization solution, which then was used to develop and launch Mars rover.
- Developed customizable inner Workflow engine, based on Aras Innovator, and WorkflowCore package.
- Accelerated x200 SQL stored procedure which indexed files for full-text search subsystem.
- Accelerated x50 method which opens search panels for complicated full-text search configurations.

#### 06.2021 - 12.2022

# Senior .NET Developer at Epam LT

Overcomplicated FinTech system

- Bugfixed C# and VB.NET multi-threading code with remote calls.
- Refactored plugins system.
- Mentored junior developers.
- · Conducted technical interviews.

# Also worked in (08.2008 - 03.2023):

- iTechArt Group LT
- Godel Technologies Europe
- Visutech Systems
- MODIS-M
- Belarussian State Publishing House
- Belhard Group